Hey, Kobato!
Sorry!
Are we getting a Christmas cake from Tirol again this year?
Yeah.
Santa's coming, right?
Of course.
What are you doing, Yuzuru?
I'm making it so it can hold tons of presents!
I'll help out!
Oww...
Sorry!
Don't worry about it.
What shall I do?
Even the obvious things are always so hard
I just want to grin when I'm happy, sing when I'm in love
They say my dreams will come true someday
but when will someday come? I can't wait!
Count one, two, three and spread my arms
Gather the light to myself
Where is it? Tell me what I can do
Even if I'm hurt so much, even if I run so hard
Even if I collapse crying over and over, I still
believe in my amazing future
That's a Santa outfit, isn't it.
Yeah. Every year, Fujimoto dresses up as Santa.
No one else here can do it.
That's right. Thanks.
... White Christmas.
I wonder if Fujimoto's mad at me again.
Dobato.
Yes?
There's something more important for you to worry about.
Candy, dammit! Candy!
Yes!
Kobato!
Domoto!
I've been waiting. You worn out from staying late at work?
No, I'm fine!
I'll walk you home, if you don't mind.
That's... Thanks!
The sparkling lights at Christmas are so wonderful.
You're right. Is there anything you want, Kobato?
Something I want?
Well... Thanks to the bazaar, we were able to buy new toys...
So I can pick a present I think suits you?
For me?
Well, it is Christmas.
I wonder what I should get you.
Yo. You're working pretty hard on Christmas.
Whatever. I don't care if it's Christmas.
Is something wrong?
Nothing.
Kobato?
It's nothing.
Let's go.
See you.
Kobato, haven't you made up with Kiyokazu yet?
I think he really hates me now.
He's acting different from normal.
He doesn't tease me.
He won't even look straight at me.
I see.
I've been so worried about it...
It's not your fault, Kobato. I'm sure Kiyokazu doesn't blame you.
He just can't tell you up front.
It'll be fine.
Okay...
Thank you!
No prob.
Wanna get together tomorrow?
Sure!
All right, I'll be waiting.
Right in front of the nursery.
But you'll get cold!
I'll be waiting.
But...
I'll be fine.
All right, see you tomorrow.
Okay.
It's Christmassy at home!
I've got to get you a present, Ioryogi!
What would you like?
A bottle full of candy.
O-Okay!
Oh, that's right! I made this for you!
Here!
Now you're a reindeer!
Dobato!
Oh man.
I'm gonna be late!
Good morning!
You're up earlier than usual, Kobato.
Yeah, we have to get ready for the Christmas party.
Oh.
Kobato, you should come over to our place if you don't have anything planned.
We're having a Christmas party.
Mama's gonna cook something tasty!
You should come if you have time.
Of course! Thanks!
Good morning.
Fujimoto, you should come to our Christmas party too!
I have to work tonight.
Plus, Christmas is...
Work hard, okay? See you.
All right, you two need to get going too.
All right!
Here we go!
Kobato?
Everyone has so much fun at Christmas...
It's just Fujimoto that seems so sad.
I really must have done something to set him off.
That's not it.
Kiyokazu has been alone ever since that Christmas Eve.
To Mommy
Mommy!
Are you okay, boy?
I'm fine.
Very well, then.
Kiyokazu's mother never came back.
Just after than, Sayaka's father took him in.
Sorry I'm late.
It's okay.
All right, let's start the Christmas party.
I'm changed.
Come in when everyone calls for you.
Okay.
Kobato.
Yeah?
Get changed, and let's get started.
Kobato?
Fujimoto's so mature...
Yeah, he is.
So, so mature...
I'll try my best too!
There, there.
Okay, let's all call for Santa!
Yay!
Santa!
It's Santa!
Santa's here!
Santa!
Wait, are you just Mister Kiyokazu?
No, it's Santa!
Santa?
Is it Mister Kiyokazu?
This is Santa!
Aren't you Santa, Santa?
I wonder what presents we're all getting from Santa?
Presents from Santa!
A present for me!
Thanks!
Thank you, Santa!
All right, it's time for the cake!
Oof!
Time to go get my present.
Good work, Fujimoto.
I'll clean up. Cheer up, it's Christmas.
Quit worrying about me.
Man, why me?
Shut up. Christmas is rush season.
You're overworking me.
Merry Christmas!
What are you doing?
That doesn't suit you at all.
Kobato!
Kobato?
I see. Kiyokazu is so distant because it's Christmas.
I think I've hurt him even worse now.
He hates me even more now...
That's...
That's-!
Why does it hurt this much!?
You're that worried about Kiyokazu?
I can't stop thinking of him.
I don't know why, but my heart aches every time I do.
I see.
Domoto?
I know what the best present for you is now.
Thank you.
I have a Christmas present.
Don't get me wrong, it's not for you.
Kobato's at the outlook. Bring this to her.
Go for it, I'll cover for you here.
Wait, why me?
She's awfully sad for Christmas.
So-
You're hurting her!
But she thinks it's her own fault...
She wants to apologize to you.
Kobato's waiting for you.
She's waiting alone.
Fujimoto?
It's not your fault!
You didn't do anything wrong. You don't need to worry.
So quit worrying.
Does this mean you're not mad?
Haven't I been telling you that this whole time!?
Now you're mad!
Anyway, please don't worry.
Okay.
That's right. Domoto sent this.
Umm...
You've made up, right?
This is my present to you.
Sorry if he's mean to you.
Merry Christmas.
You're my present from Domoto?
What did Domoto even say to you?
"I have the perfect present for you, Kobato. Let me go get it."
Domoto let me make up with you.
That son of a...
Hey, wait!
It's snowing, Fujimoto!
No kidding.
It's so pretty!
The flowers which blossom in spring
Are plucked in the summer sun
Within my heart
Their shine remains
Even on days I close my windows to shut out the morning rain
Fluttering within my heart, the light breaks through the clouds
Joy and sadness, I embrace them both and keep going
My hand and yours join together strongly
The snow is really pretty.
Yeah!
A faraway voice leads me on
No matter what happens, once winter's over and spring comes...
I say goodbye to Kobato.
Like it's smiling, like it's singing
The echoing sound of the wind
People all want to fly
but they're cheated by gravity
everyone can really fly
She must be so unhappy because
she forgot her own shadow somewhere
Then...
If you tell me "thanks", if you say "thanks" and smile
Going back and forth, we'll be happy
You'll be happy, there'll be nothing to worry about
As long as we're together
It's strange, I'm crying even though I'm happy
... The Wanderer.
Next episode